[music]
>> Welcome to the 2026 release wave one of
Business Central launch edition. In this
video, we're going to talk about
enhanced sales analytics.
The reason we invest in this is we want
to still set focus on better analytics
to to get better more profitability and
more sales. And here in this wave we
focus on customer loyalty. Being able to
analyze recurring and churn customers
and just more easy built-in reporting
for sales.
So, I'm going to demo things from
starting in Power BI for sales.
A little bit about just mentioning item
ABC analysis even though it's inventory,
it still relates to sales all the way
down to new demo data for sales
analytics. So, let's get started.
In the Power BI app for sales, I
promised last semester that we would
done and we couldn't help it. We just
had one more thing that we wanted to
add, which is customer retention
overview and history. Two new reports
that simply allows you to see whether
your customers are recurring, whether
they are churning and whether they are
going back
going back to you either by geography
by customer.
And and kind of see that that picture of
your business as well. So, that's the
overview, but then you can also go into
a more historical representation of the
same data where you can see new
recurring customers over time.
All the way down to temporary lost or
real lost customer. Temporary lost
meaning
you lost them, but they kind of got
back. Lost customers you haven't seen
since that first initial
whenever they stopped buying.
So, hopefully this can help you
also making sure that you focus on
loyalty for customers so the customers
keeps buying with you and are
not churning.
Related to sales, but as I said mostly
in inventory is something called ABC
analysis. ABC analysis allows you to
divide your inventory of items in
categories A, B, and C
where you say that category A items must
always be on inventory because you are
these are the ones that you sell the
most, right? So, even though it's an
exercise in supply chain making sure you
always have things on stock, you can
also use this in a sales situation or a
sales analysis where you you look at
the things that that sell based on like
the first 50% and so on. However, you
partition your A, B, and C's.
So, it's a new report in the inventory
app.
It also actually comes and it go to the
inventory analytics session. There's a
link for that to see it. It also comes
in an Excel version so you don't have to
use Power BI for this.
We got some feedback for for the sales
reports that we that we shipped in the
fall of 2025. We shipped these
six five six sales reports with Excel
layouts and
for these they the initial version was
missed. They the pivot tables were
missing subtotals. It's a very simple
change so we decided let's let's just
ship this out of the box in this wave.
If you want these on your own reports of
the older version, it's just a simple
check mark
in the pivot table and you get to this.
But these these five reports now come
with a little better analysis with
subtotals.
And then
in this release wave we are adding the
ability to ship analysis tabs or
analysis views with the with with AL
apps or with the AL code. So, we decided
also to to ship some out of the box
reports reports in the sales area. So,
on the sales order list we're shipping
three analysis views out of the box.
They are coming in 28.x so not in the
April release, so but once once we get a
few months out you should be able to see
these surface in your application.
Finally, we added mainly if you're
demoing both Power BI and other reports
in the sales area, we added extended or
enhanced the demo data for sales.
There's a full session on demo data so
check that out. But in sales we added
the number of open sales orders and back
orders
as well as the data distribution. So,
you can actually tell much better data
stories in sales in the new demo data.
If you want to learn more in
analytics around sales, then go to this
link aka.ms/bcsalesanalytics.
This will take you to that landing page
on the sales where you can both
examine or learn about Power BI,
the out of the box reports with Excel or
even ad hoc analysis using analysis
mode.
If you're interested in this topic with
sales analytics, chances are that you
probably also like it in other areas.
So, go to these related sessions going
from inventory analytics all the way
down to our enhanced
analysis mode. Those sessions are linked
in the description here. So, so I hope
you that you will also
watch some if not all of them.
And that's it. If you already know the
Business Central resources here, then
skip the video. If you don't, stick
around for for a few more minutes. This
video on sales analytics is over and I
wish you a great rest of your launch
launch edition.
Bye.
We have compiled a number of general
resources that we believe are key both
for partners, but also Business Central
customers. Most Some of these are
partner, some of them are also for
customers. So, the first one is
called aka.ms/bcall.
This is a partner resource for that
contains lists of every other aka link
that is needed for you to understand
anything about both the Business Central
product, but also processes around it.
We call these aka links because they are
called aka.ms and then for forward slash
something. And with Business Central
links we all always prefix with BC and
then something.
The next one is our partner network
social media for for Business Central
partners Viva Viva Engage. So,
aka.ms/bcvivaengage
is where you go and interact with other
partners. It's not open for customers.
So, this is where you can ask questions,
interact with the product group,
interact with with with each other
in a in a closed network.
Second link a third link is for both
partners and customers. We are called
office hours. So, office hours is
something we do once or twice a month
from the product group engaging with the
community about new features or things
we want to discuss. aka.ms/bcofficehours
is the is the place where you go to find
out about upcoming events.
These are recorded. I believe the
recordings are available only to
partners, but the live events are
available to customers as well.
Fourth link is YouTube our YouTube
channel. I'll talk about that
in the next slide and LinkedIn in the
next slide.
And then finally for for Microsoft
partners the BC's aka.ms/bcpartnerportal
is where you get
a lot of the resources
as a partner such as compete decks,
pitch decks, and a lot of other
resources.
For LinkedIn, this is our product
group's LinkedIn profile. We have 30K or
more followers. So, both partners and
customers. This is the place where we
from the product group put in news and
small bits of information outside the
quote unquote official channel. So,
follow us on LinkedIn to learn what's
happening right now
in in this in the around the product.
And then
also on our YouTube channel where this
is where you're probably watching this
aka.ms/bcyoutube.
We put in not only these launch editions
twice a year, but also
co-pilot and AI videos, shorts, tips and
tricks, technical deep dives, under the
hoods.
We even have this what's cooking where
we put little nuggets of of videos out
for new features that are even coming in
on the YouTube channel before
they are coming in the release notes.
So, watch
and maybe bookmark us on YouTube. And
also notice all the playlists. So, that
all the content is also organized in
areas, not only all the videos. So, if
you have an area that has special
interest such as analytics,
you can find an
a playlist and kind of see all the
content related to that.
And that's it. That is truly it. We
won't
there will be no more. So, thank you for
watching all the way to the end.
And again, have a great day. Thank you.